hey everyone this is Adrian from PI
image search comm today I'm going to
show you how to build a mobile scanner
app similar to apps such as genius can
now perhaps you've seen these these
mobile scanning apps before but the
general premise is that you know you
have a piece of paper a document or
receipt I need to scan it so you pull
out your phone and snap a photo of it
and then magically it's scanned into a
PDF there's apps like Pina scan you've
got turbo scan and you got scanner pro
you just have tons of apps that
basically do the same thing they allow
you to take a picture of a document and
scan it into your phone it's a really
cool concept but you may be wondering
what's the computer vision that goes
into it and how does it work well that's
exactly what this post is going to
answer for so you have an example image
here I'm just going to pull this up so
the first step we're going to perform is
edge detection so over here on the Left
I have a piece of paper from practical
Python and OpenCV my computer vision
book that I route and the first step
we're going to do here it's poor mesh
detection we're going to find the
outline of that piece of paper after we
do that we're going to find the contours
of that piece of paper or the outline of
it then we can apply a slightly longer
step of actually applying the four-point
Transformer perspective warp and we're
also going to threshold it to give it
that classic black and white paper feel
so here's the final result compared to
the original originals over here on the
left and on the right we have heart
we have successfully scanned our piece
of paper notice how the perspective has
been transformed to give us this
top-down bird's-eye view and also notice
how we have a strictly black and white
image now you can see over here it's not
always is the perspective of but you
have a lot of gray tones in the paper
but over here it's nice and scanned and
looks looks all pretty so to get a full
view of all the code that that I have
here check out the rest of this blog
post I think you really can enjoy
you